A Guide to the Thomas Tyler Bouldin Papers, 1834-1850
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg
Thomas Tyler Bouldin Papers, 1834-1850.
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 87.3
30 items.
Thomas Tyler Bouldin.; Hezekiah Brooks.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Dept. of Collections, 1987.
Biographical/Historical Information
Thomas Tyler Bouldin was apparently the son of Congressman Thomas T. Bouldin and a grandson of Major Wood Bouldin and Joanna Tyler Bouldin.
Scope and Content Information
Papers of Thomas Tyler Bouldin, Hezahiah Brooks, Sr., and others include bills, accounts, promissory notes, receipts, letters, and some legal documents. The papers concern family matters, clothing, tobacco, Gilliam family history, and a fine for not attending muster. Includes correspondents from Charlottesville, Charlotte County, and elsewhere. These papers were found inside an eighteenth-century spinet owned by Joanna Tyler Bouldin.
Arrangement
Chronologically arranged.
Index Terms
Family Names:
Gilliam family.
Persons:
Bouldin, Thomas Tyler.; Bouldin, Joanna Tyler, d. 1845.; Brooks, Hezekiah.
Subjects:
Tobacco--Virginia--History--19th century.
Geographical Names:
Charlotte County (Va.)--History--19th century.; Charlottesville (Va.)--History--19th century.
Genre and Form Terms:
Promissory notes--Virginia--19th century.; Receipts--Virginia--19th century.
Contents List
- Bill for clothing. Jno. Cochnar to Thomas T. Bouldin, 8 November 1834-20 January 1835.
- Account of Hezikiah Brooks with James McGraw, 1 April 1836-18 December 1839.
- Bill to Hez[ikiah] Brooks, Sr. for services of the clerk of Halifax Circuit Sup. Co., April 1838.
- Promissory note. Hezikiah Brooks, Sr. to McGraw, Barksdale & Co., 3 March 1839.
- Account of Mr. Guysee with H. Hall, 5 November 1840-21 December 1840.
- Bill to James Hill for not attending the October muster of Captain Milner, 1840.
- Fragment of tailoring account of Jno. Patterson, 1840.
- Draft of promissory note. John D. Richardson to Elisha E. Hundley and [William?] Bailey, 1 November 1841.
- Fragment of an account of Thomas T. Bouldin for 35 soda tickets, 1841.
- Promissory note. Richard Walne to Addison Irvine, 1 March 1842.
- Account of Benjamin Lax, April 1842.
- Account of Hezikiah Brooks with McGraw & Co., 24 October 1842.
- Fragment. Note on a document filed in Lynchburg, Hustings Court, 31 October 1842.
- Receipt to Thomas T. Bouldin from Winslow Robinson, 4 September 1843.
- Letter re collection of a debt. J. Read, Charleston, to Thomas T. Bouldin, Charlotv..., 18 November 1844.
- Account of Mr. Murphy with Read & Flournay, 1845.
- Fragment of bill of Wood Bou[ldin] from [Tho]mas Anderson, May 1846.
- Bond account of Thomas T. Bouldin with Clairborne Barksdale, 25 December 1846.
- Account of Doctor's visits. Jesse Wilkes with Dr. John P. Brown, 18 August 1847-1 January 1849.
- Account of Wood Bouldin with J. Dupuy, 5 January 1849.
- Receipt. Mr. Ward (?) Furguson to Mitchell & Tyler, Richmond, 1849.
- Letter re Gilliam family history. William E. Gilliam, Cornissville, Marshall County, Mississppi to Thomas T. Bouldin, 21 August 1850.
- Bond. William Baldwin to Charles Hutchinson, 26 December 1850.
- Tobacco account of Hezikiah Brooks, Jr., n.d.
- Letter fragment to Thomas T. Bouldin, n.d.
- Order to the sheriff of Lynchburg, n.d.
- Letter to George W. Read, Charlotte County, n.d.
- Letter re a slave to [Thomas?] Bouldin, n.d.
- Promissory note. Armistead Say to McGraw, Barksdale & Co., 27 March, n.y.
- Legal document of William H. Barksdale, 25 April n.y.